We present cross-embodied co-design for dexterous robot hands.
Traditionally, robot bodies are designed first and a method
for control second.
This can lead to suboptimal designs and control pairs
for challenging tasks.
We show developing control and design together can lead
to improved task performance.
Our co-design framework aims to bridge this gap by
generating robot hands and control together.
We provide a framework to generate, evaluate, and control
robot hands with complementary controls, sim-to-real.
First, we create cross-embodied policies which work across robot
hand variations from a randomly generated robot hand dataset.
Next, we generate and evaluate designs using modular parts,
learned design rules, and design-conditioned policies.
Finally, we manufacture our robot hands and deploy them
sim-to-real.
We deploy across multiple robot hands and three tasks
in simulation.
In-hand rotation: the robot hand must rotate randomized objects
around the x-axis.
Object grasping: this tests the ability to create design
and control with quick and stable grasps.
Object flipping: the robot hand has a fixed wrist
and is asked to rotate randomized objects on the z-axis.
To quickly develop multiple robot hands we created a modular
platform where palms, fingertips, degrees of freedom, finger lengths,
and shapes can be easily altered.
The build guide is available on our website.
We show trade-offs for design and control strategies and
the ability of our framework to accurately predict design ranking
sim-to-real by testing four robot hands on a blind
in-hand rotation.
Top is the best found design for in-hand rotation —
a three-finger design which provides the maximum torque while providing
the minimum points required to define a stable circumference
of rotation.
Bottom is our baseline human-like hand which has five
fingers with a human-like layout.
We show two additional designs sim-to-real to demonstrate the
ability of our framework to predict design-control ranking accurately.
Our paper and robot hand build guide are available
on our website.